Theon: Maester Luwin,
send a raven to Pyke
www.tvsubtitles.net
informing my father
of my victory here.
And one to Deepwood Motte
to my sister.
Inform her that she's to
bring 500 men to Winterfell.
When do we sail
for King's Landing?
Soon as I've consolidated
my troops.
And you lead the fleet
into Blackwater Bay.
The fist of the First Men.
Thousands of years ago
the First Men stood here.
They came here to get
away from something.
And I don't think
it worked.
Cersei: Do you really think I'll let
you ship Myrcella off to Dorne?
Dorne is the safest
place for her.
I want you to know what
it's like to love someone,
to truly love someone
before I take her from you.
You let a halfwit escape
with a cripple?
And Rickon, too?
The little one?
Gone, along with
the wildling woman.
Wait, I know that farm.
- They'll give us some food.
- We can't risk it.
I've been treating
your wounded men.
I've already run through the
supplies I brought with me.
You're riding to the Crag
to negotiate a surrender.
Come with me to the Crag. Let
the Maester show you his stores.
( Grunts )
( Whistles )
Should have took me
while you had the chance.
Catelyn:
They want your head.
Old Lord Karstark
doesn't seem to like me.
You strangled his son
with your chains.
- He was in my way.
- You are a man without honor.
Brienne, your sword.
You have my dragons?
I will take you to
the House of the Undying
where I have put them.
( Groans )
Your dragons wait for you
in the House of the Undying.
I told you what would happen
if you served me loyally
and what would happen
if you did not.
What have you done?
If there are any among
you who still question
whether your new lord
means what he says...
No!
( Theme music playing )
♪ Game of Thrones 2x08 ♪
The Prince of Winterfell
Original Air Date on May 20, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
( Creaks )
- Man: Rider approaching!
- Man #2: Open the gate!
( Creaking )
( Horses neighing )
- Why, it's the Prince of Winterfell.
- ( Men laugh )
- Envy isn't attractive.
- What envy?
You should be proud
of your brother's achievement.
I took the great castle
of Winterfell with 20 men.
You're a great warrior.
I saw the bodies
above your gates.
Which one gave you
the tougher fight,
the cripple or
the six-year-old?
( Men laugh )
I treated the Stark
boys with honor
and they repaid me
with treachery.
You treated them with honor
by butchering them?
Before I had to kill them,
I treated them--
you seized their home,
as is your right.
- We're Ironborn; We take what we need.
- Exactly.
Then you made them prisoners in
their home and they ran away.
Is that treachery?
I'd call it bravery.
They made me a promise--
Your little boy prisoners
made you a promise
and you got mad
when they broke it?
Are you the dumbest
cunt alive?
- Don't call me a--
- A cunt.
A dumb cunt who killed
the only two Starks in Winterfell.
You know how valuable
those boys were?
If I hadn't killed them, the
Northerners would think me weak.
You are weak.
And you're stupid.
I'm warning you.
Go on, then,
warn me.
You haven't brought
enough men.
How am I supposed to defend
Winterfell with just this lot?
You're not. I've come to bring
you home.
- Father wants a word.
- Is this a joke?
Winterfell is the heart
of the North.
Aye, it is, hundreds of miles
from the sea.
We're islanders,
baby brother.
Had you forgotten that?
Our power comes
from our ships.
And now that you've
decorated your walls
with the bodies
of the Stark boys,
every man in the North
wants to see you hanged.
When Robb Stark
finds out--
He won't find out.
We've killed all the ravens.
We have all the horses.
I've taken Winterfell.
And I will keep Winterfell.
Leave us.
Theon, you're my blood.
We both loved our mother.
We both endured
our father.
Come home with me.
Don't die here alone.
I don't intend to die.
You were a terrible baby,
do you know that?
Bawling all the time,
never sleeping.
And one night you just
wouldn't shut up,
screaming like a dying pig.
I walked over to your crib,
I looked down at you.
I wanted to strangle you.
And you looked up at me
and you stopped screaming.
You smiled at me.
Don't die
so far from the sea.
I've brought you
a present, Lord of Bones.
I already got one crow.
Don't need two.
Mance will want
to question this one.
Knows all about where the crows
are and what they're planning.
The Halfhand knows more.
This one is just a little boy.
Gut him.
He could have killed me
half a dozen times.
And now he wishes he did.
Gut him.
He's a bastard of Winterfell,
Ned Stark's son.
Mance will want him.
What does Mance want
with a dead man's bastard?
I don't know.
I think he'll want
to decide for himself.
He runs, I'll chop
his balls off.
He runs,
I'll do it meself.
We're even now,
Jon Snow.
I couldn't do it.
I had the sword at her neck,
I just couldn't--
- I know.
- The others?
When you didn't come back,
we went looking for you.
We found your tracks
fast enough.
But they found us
before we found you.
They died because of me.
See that it wasn't
for nothing.
All right, up, lad.
Come on,
on your feet, now.
Move it.
( Birds calling,
water burbling )
Is she beautiful?
I've never met her.
What's her name?
Frey, I suppose.
I don't know
her first name.
I'm sure you'll
be very happy.
( Both laugh )
And you're marrying
her for a bridge?
- An important bridge.
- Ah.
It was before
they killed my father.
I still thought I could march south
and rescue him in time,
but only if I crossed
that bridge.
When I speak to people
from the North,
they all loved
your father.
He was the best man
I ever met.
I know children always think
that about their fathers, but--
Children do not always think that
about their fathers,
believe me.
He once told me that being
a Lord is like being a father,
except you have
thousands of children
and you worry about
all of them.
The farmers plowing
the fields are yours to protect.
The charwomen scrubbing the floors,
yours to protect.
The soldiers
you order into battle.
He told me he woke
with fear in the morning
and went to bed
with fear in the night.
I didn't believe him.
I asked him,
"how can a man be brave
if he's afraid?"
"That is the only time
a man can be brave," he told me.
I wish I could have
met him.
He would have
liked you.
Most Lords worry more
about their gold
and their glory than the charwomen
scrubbing their floors.
He didn't care much
about gold or glory.
And you?
You think I'm fighting this war so
they'll sing songs about me?
I want to go home.
I want the men
following me to go home.
Then why don't you?
Because we'll never be safe until
the Lannisters are defeated.
And because I believe
in justice.
Chopping off
Joffrey's head, you mean.
That would be a start.
( Horse neighs,
hoofbeats approaching )
Your Grace, Milady.
The Kingslayer,
he escaped in the night.
How?
How?!
Tell me this isn't true.
Why?
- For the girls.
- You betrayed me.
- Robb--
- No!
You knew I would
not allow it
and you did it
anyway.
Bran and Rickon
are captives in Winterfell.
Sansa and Arya are captives
in King's Landing.
I have five children,
and only one of them is free.
I lost one son fighting
by your son's side.
I lost another
to the Kingslayer,
strangled with a chain.
You commit treason
because your children
are prisoners?
I would carve out
my heart
and offer it to the father
if he would let my sons
wake from their graves
and step into a prison cell.
I grieve for
your sons, My Lord.
I don't want your grief.
I want my vengeance.
And you stole it
from me.
Killing Jaime Lannister
would not buy life
for your children,
but returning him
to King's Landing
may buy life
for mine.
Jaime Lannister has played
you for a fool.
You've weakened
our position.
You've brought discord
into our camp.
And you did it all
behind my back.
Make sure she's guarded
day and night.
Robb.
How many men did we send
in pursuit of the Kingslayer?
40, Your Grace.
Send another 40
with our fastest horses.
Robb.
( Neighing )
Whoa, oof!
( Groans )
Damn.
You're much uglier
in daylight.
What's your name?
I'm Jaime Lannister
of Casterly Rock,
son of Tywin.
A captive Knight has a right
to know his captor's identity.
Brienne of Tarth.
Tarth, Tarth, Tarth.
Crescent moons
and starbursts.
Lord... Selwyn Tarth,
your father.
Do you have any brothers
and sisters, My Lady?
It's a long way
to King's Landing.
Might as well get
to know one another.
Have you known many men?
I suppose not.
Women?
Horses?
Ah!
I didn't mean to give
offense, My Lady.
Forgive me.
Your crimes are past
forgiveness, Kingslayer.
Why do you
hate me so much?
- Have I ever harmed you?
- You've harmed others--
those you were
sworn to protect,
the weak,
the innocent.
Has anyone ever told you you're
as boring as you are ugly?
You will not
provoke me to anger.
I already have.
Look at you.
You're ready
to chop my head off.
Do you think
you could?
Do you think you could
beat me in a fair fight?
I've never
seen you fight.
The answer is no.
There are three men
in the kingdoms who might
have a chance against me.
You're not one of them.
All my life men like you
have sneered at me.
And all my life I've been knocking
men like you into the dust.
If you're so confident,
unlock my chains.
Let's see what happens.
Do you take me
for an idiot? In.
I took you
for a fighter,
a man-- pardon--
woman of honor.
Was I wrong?
You're afraid.
Maybe one day
we'll find out, Kingslayer.
Kevan: King's Landing
will fall an hour
after Stannis
lands his force.
It's not too late for
King Joffrey and Cersei
and the court
to ride west to safety.
Surrender the Iron Throne?
Better than seeing their heads
mounted on the city gates.
Stannis will
execute them all.
No, a king who runs
will not be king for long.
He's a Lannister.
He'll stand and fight.
Stannis, two days
from the capital
and the wolf
at my doorstep.
The scouts assure us Robb Stark
remains north of Ashemark.
Ha! The last time
the scouts assured us
of Stark's movement,
he lured us into a trap.
Which is why my son
is his prisoner.
Too close
to Casterly Rock.
He sent a splinter force
to recapture Winterfell.
The Greyjoys have
done us a great favor.
Stark won't risk marching
on Casterly Rock
until he's at full force.
He's a boy and he's
never lost a battle.
He'll risk anything
at any time
because he doesn't know
enough to be afraid.
We'll ride at nightfall.
I want a full night's march before
he knows we're on the move.
Clegane, you'll maintain
a garrison here at Harrenhal.
Track down this brotherhood
and destroy them.
The girl has proven
herself a good servant.
She'll stay on with you.
See that he doesn't get
drunk in the evenings.
He's poor company
when he's sober,
but he's better
at his work.
You've got some
questions to answer.
Man:
Who killed Ser Amory?
- Man #2: I don't know!
- Give me the name.
- Man #2: Please!
- Man #3: Take this one out for the crows.
Man #2:
I told you, I don't know.
Please.
Look, it's Yoren's
little cunt.
Used to be a boy,
now it's a girl.
- ( Man laughs )
- Where's Jaqen?
Don't care.
Where's your stick
now, bitch?
I promised
to fuck you with it.
Guard: Come on, time to kill
some wolves.
( Men shouting )
You need sour cherries
to make it right.
And the secret is you dry
the stones, and then you
break them with a mallet.
That's where
the real flavor is.
You crush 'em up real fine.
And then when you're finished,
you sprinkle them over the piecrust.
- Where's Jaqen?
- How would I know?
I need him now.
Lord Tywin's
marching tonight.
- You need him?
- He's helping me.
- Hot Pie: I saw him.
- Where?
- Where?!
- Ow!
Where?
They went riding out
the gates a few hours ago.
On patrol.
Let go of my ears.
( Horses neighing,
men shouting )
What do you want
with him anyway?
( Men shouting )
( Wind howling )
Qhorin: Mance is gonna
march on the Wall.
When he does, one brother
inside his army
will be worth 1,000
fighting against it.
- They'll never trust me.
- They might...
- If you do what needs to be done.
- What?
How does it feel knowing
those men all died
so you could skip through the
snow with your little savage girl?
I didn't.
I should have known better,
trusting a traitor's bastard.
He's not yours
to kill, crow.
Do you have
to do that here?
I like to keep
me hands clean.
Yes, but do you
have to do it here?
You should start wearing
the gold cloak.
I don't want to wear
a gold cloak.
You're commander
of the City Watch.
You shouldn't be dressed
like a common sellsword.
A cloak slows you down
in a fight,
makes it hard
to move quietly.
And the gold
catches the light,
so you're nice and easy
to spot at night.
Well, you're not sneaking
through alleyways any longer.
You're supposed
to stand out.
We had a deal, and wearing
a gold cloak wasn't part of it.
Fine, fine.
No gold cloak.
- What?
What? What?
Why are you staring at me?
( Scoffs ) You don't want me
cleaning me nails.
You don't want me
looking your way.
Why am I here?
To help me plan the defense
of King's Landing.
( Laughs )
Stannis will be here
any day.
( Sighs )
And one of these
explains how to beat him?
"An History of the Great
Sieges of Westeros"
by Archmaester
"Shevelathin."
"Shevelatesh."
"Chevalteesh."
I'd swap all your books
for a few good archers.
My Lord Hand,
Commander.
I must compliment you
on the Gold Cloaks' performance
these last few weeks.
Did you know there has been
a marked drop in thievery?
I did not know.
And how did you accomplish
this marked drop in thievery?
Me and the lads rounded up
all the known thieves.
For questioning?
Uh, no.
It's just the unknown thieves
we need to worry about now.
- We talked about this.
- Aye, we talked about it.
Have you ever been
in a city under siege?
Maybe this part's
not in your books.
See, it's not the fighting
that kills most people.
It's the starving.
Food's worth more than gold.
Noble ladies sell their diamonds
for a sack of potatoes.
Things get bad enough,
the poor start
eating each other.
The thieves,
they love a siege.
Soon as the gates are sealed,
they steal all the food.
By the time it's all over,
they're the richest men in town.
Given the circumstances,
My Lord,
I believe extreme measures
are warranted.
Ah.
"The Great Sieges
of Westeros."
Thrilling subject.
Shame Archmaester Ch'vyalthan
wasn't a better writer.
Stannis knows
King's Landing.
He knows where the walls
are strongest
and he knows which gates
are weakest.
The mud gate.
A good ram will batter it
down in minutes
and it's only 50 yards
from the water.
That's where he'll land.
And if Stannis does
attack the mud gate,
what is our plan?
We could throw
books at his men.
We don't have
that many books.
that many men, either.
What do we have?
Pig shit.
( Wind howling )
( Chatter )
( Panting )
I'm not cut out
for this sort of work.
I always imagined meself
doing something much worse.
We're digging latrine pits
at the end of the world.
I can't imagine
anything much worse.
Dolorous Edd:
You lack imagination.
Sam: Where do you think
Jon is right now?
He went off with the Halfhand.
He didn't come back.
A betting man
would go with dead.
He's not dead.
No, Jon's a great
fighter.
Well, he's better
than me
and a lot better
than you.
He's got a Valyrian
steel sword.
So did his father.
And Qhorin Halfhand
is the greatest ranger alive.
Great rangers never
get old is the problem.
Shit ones neither.
It's them in the middle
that last a long time.
( Clangs )
What in seven hells
is that?
The First Men
made these marks.
Help me with it.
( Straining )
Look.
If you find something
you're not supposed to,
best thing to do is pretend
you've never seen it.
That's a Night's
Watch cloak.
It's been here
a long time.
Oh, must be Dragonglass.
Grenn:
Dragonglass?
The Maesters
call it Obsidian.
Why would a brother
hide it here?
I expect it's 'cause
he wanted somebody to find it.
Mind where you're going.
I'm sorry.
I'll--
- where were you?
- A man has patrol duty.
Tywin Lannister
was right here
and now he's gone.
A girl owes
one more name.
The Red God demands it.
Give the man a name.
How long after
I give you the name
does it take you
to kill someone?
A minute, an hour,
a month.
Death is certain,
the time is not.
He's taking his army
to attack my brother.
I need him dead
right now.
This a man
cannot do.
You promised
you'd help me.
Help was not promised,
lovely girl.
Only death.
There must be others.
Give a name,
any name.
And you'll kill them?
Anybody?
By the seven New Gods
and the Old Gods beyond counting,
I swear it.
All right.
Jaqen H'ghar.
A girl gives a man
his own name?
- That's right.
- Gods are not mocked.
- This is no joking thing.
- I'm not joking.
A man can go kill himself.
- Un-name me.
- No.
Please?
I'll un-name you.
Thank you.
If you help me
and my friends escape.
This would require
more than one life.
- This is not part of our bargain.
- Fine, Jaqen H'ghar.
A girl lacks honor.
If I do this thing,
a girl must obey.
A girl will obey.
A girl and her friends will walk
through the gate at midnight.
Thank you, Podrick.
Odd little boy.
I have a certain sympathy
for odd little boys.
You and Varys both.
Excellent lamprey pie.
Were you slaving away
in the kitchen all day?
I hear Joffrey
plans on fighting.
An inspiration
for the troops.
The young king
in his shining armor
fighting to defend the capital
against the wicked old rebel.
He's only a boy.
Younger boys are off
fighting his war.
He's not ready.
What is he, 17?
- Remember Jaime at 17?
- Better than you.
Some men have a gift
for this sort of thing,
some don't.
His place is not
on the battlefield.
It's not on
the throne, either,
sadly for all of us.
Do you think
I'm an idiot?
No, I'd say you possess
above average intelligence.
You shipped off
my only daughter.
And now you want to send my
eldest son to the battlefield to die.
He'll have his Kingsguard
protecting him.
He has the finest armor
gold can buy.
He needs to be out there.
The men will fight more
fiercely seeing their king
fighting beside them
instead of hiding behind
his mother's skirts.
Any dessert?
Do you know why
Varys is so dangerous?
Because he has thousands
of spies in his employ.
Because he knows everything
we do before we do it.
Because he doesn't
have a cock.
Neither do you.
Perhaps I'm dangerous, too.
You, on the other hand,
are as big a fool
as every other man.
That little worm
between your legs
does half your thinking.
- It's not that little.
- ( Laughs )
Why are you smiling?
Because I'm happy.
And why are you happy?
Because I have
your little whore.
I thought you
preferred blondes.
Such a droll little fellow.
Tell me, have you
married this one yet?
No?
Oh, good.
Father will be so pleased.
Why do you care
who I fuck?
Because a Lannister
always pays her debts.
You stole my only daughter,
you plot to have
Joffrey killed.
This is madness.
Stannis will be here in days.
- You need me.
- For what?
Your skill in battle?
Pretty thing, your whore.
Lovely body.
The bruises
will heal in time.
Where did you find her?
Varys isn't the only one
who hears whispers.
Really, a Lannister
lion necklace?
You need to hide your secret whores
more carefully.
You've forgotten the most
important thing about whores.
Oh?
Well, you're the expert.
Tell me.
You don't buy them;
You only rent them.
You're usually a better liar,
baby brother.
This one you like.
You like her very much.
Could it be love?
Don't worry, she'll be treated
gently enough...
unless Joffrey is hurt.
And then every wound
he suffers she'll suffer, too.
And if he dies,
there isn't a man alive
who could devise
a more painful death
for your little cunt.
And how do I know you
haven't killed her already?
Would you like to see her?
I thought you might.
Ser Mandon, bring in
my brother's whore.
I'm sorry they hurt you.
You must be brave.
I promise
I will free you.
Don't forget me.
Never.
( Door opens, closes )
I will hurt you
for this.
A day will come when you
think you're safe and happy
and your joy will turn
to ashes in your mouth.
And you will know
the debt is paid.
Get out.
Shae!
I've been waiting
all night.
What is wrong?
You're beautiful.
Then why do you look sad?
We have to be
more careful.
Don't be afraid.
I can take care of myself.
There are people
who want to hurt me.
I know.
I won't let them.
I'll cut off their faces.
I will.
I would kill for you.
Do you know that?
I expect I'll have to
before this is over.
You're mine.
I'm yours.
Promise me.
I'm yours,
and you are mine.
Robb:
Still no word?
We've sent
a dozen ravens.
None have returned.
My bastard is only
a few days from Winterfell.
- Once he captures the castle--
- Theon has my brothers.
- If we storm the castle--
- He wouldn't dare hurt the boys.
They're his only hope of escaping
the North with his head.
Send word to your son.
Any Ironborn who surrender
will be allowed to return
safely to their homes.
A touch of mercy is a virtue,
Your Grace. Too much--
Any ironborn with the exception
of Theon Greyjoy.
He betrayed our cause.
He betrayed me.
And we will hunt him down
no matter where he runs.
I expect his countrymen
will turn on him the minute
they hear the offer.
Your pardon, My Lord.
Your Grace.
My Lady.
How are you?
How am I?
I've had to arrest
my mother.
The Lannisters
have my sisters.
The man I considered
my closest friend
has seized my home
and my brothers.
I'm fighting a war and I don't know
if I should march south or north.
I'm sorry.
It was a stupid question.
- I'm sorry.
- No.
Forgive me.
You're being kind.
I have no right.
You have every right.
You're a king.
That's not the kind
of king I want to be.
What kind do you
want to be?
I don't know.
The good kind.
Most kings grew up
as princes.
They spend their whole lives
preparing for the crown.
I was raised to be
Lord of Winterfell.
a proper little lady,
to play the harp
and dance the latest steps
and recite
Valyrian poetry.
I'd like to hear you
play the harp.
No.
No, you would not.
( Laughs )
How did you go from
reciting Valyrian poetry
to sawing off
men's feet?
When I was 12,
my mother and father
went to a wedding.
Weddings in Volantis
last for days, you know.
And they left me
with my little brother.
The second afternoon
they were gone
was the hottest day
in the three-year summer.
We couldn't bear to be inside,
so we ran down to the Rhoyne.
Every child in Volantis
was in the Rhoyne that day.
The rich, the poor,
we were all there,
naked, screaming, racing
to the little islands.
Drummers were playing
for coppers on the east bank.
I was treading water,
talking to a friend
when I realized
I hadn't seen my brother.
I called his name.
Then I started
screaming his name.
And then I saw him
floating facedown.
My heart just...
stopped.
I was...
I dragged him
from the water.
My friend helped me,
I think.
I don't even remember.
He was so little.
Then we pulled him
onto the riverbank...
and I screamed at him
and I shook him
and he was dead.
Just dead.
A man ran over.
He had a fish
tattoo on his face.
In Volantis the slaves
have tattoos
so you know what they are
without having to talk to them.
And this man worked
on a fishing boat.
And he pushed me
out of the way.
You have to understand,
for a slave to push
a highborn girl--
that's death for the man,
a terrible death.
But he pushed me
out of the way
and he started pressing
on my brother's chest
again and again
and again
until my brother
spat out
half of the Rhoyne
and cried out.
And the man cradled his head
and told him to be calm.
I decided
two things that day.
I would not
waste my years
planning dances and masquerades
with the other noble ladies.
And when
I came of age...
I would never live
in a slave city again.
( Sighs )
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
You told me of your problems
and I've blathered on.
I don't want to marry
the Frey girl.
I don't want you
to marry her.
But you needed
that bridge.
I hope it's a very
beautiful bridge.
( Laughs )
Hot Pie: The sour cherries was all
crushed up and ready.
Gendry: Shut up.
Probably in the piecrust
by now.
In the oven,
the nice warm oven.
Shut up.
What did you bring?
The cheese
could be better.
I did get some
nice sausages.
What did he want us
to do about those guards?
He didn't say.
He just said,
"walk through the gates.
Gendry:
What about the guards?
He didn't say anything
about the guards.
What, he left that bit out?
It's a pretty important part,
don't you think?
- We have to trust him.
- Trust him?
You trusted him to fight with us
and you set him free
- and he ran.
- I want to go back to the kitchens.
Shut up.
Stay here if you're afraid.
Hot Pie:
Arry, don't.
Away!
Reset!
If the wind holds, we'll reach
King's Landing in a day.
Will it hold?
Can't make promises
for the wind, Your Grace.
Man:
Again, pull!
I admire you, Ser Davos.
I thank you, Your Grace.
Pleased to hear it.
Some highborn fools
call you Onion Knight
and think
they insult you.
So you take the onion
for your sigil,
sew it on your coat,
fly the onion flag.
My son wishes me
to change it.
Three mermen with tridents,
something like that.
I understand why the older
families look down at me.
Do you?
Why?
- My father was a crabber.
- And?
Well, sons of Lords don't like to
break bread with sons of crabbers.
Our hands stink.
And where were those Lords
when Storm's End starved?
Many fought bravely
for your brother.
Many fought
for the Mad King.
You defend these men
who insult you behind your back.
Some are happy
to do it to my face.
We were forgotten.
Robert and Ned Stark--
they were the heroes,
the glorious rebels marching
from battle to battle,
liberating towns from
the yoke of the Mad King
while I held Storm's End
with 500 men.
- No one has forgotten, Your Grace.
- No? Robert did.
He gave Storm's End
to Renly after the war.
Renly never fought
a day in his life.
- He was only a boy.
- Then why'd he give him Storm's End?
First we ate the horses.
We weren't riding anyway,
not with the castle surrounded.
We couldn't feed them,
so fine, the horses.
Then the cats.
Never liked cats.
So fine.
I do like dogs.
Good animals.
Loyal.
But we ate them.
Then the rats.
The night before
you slipped through,
I thought my wife
was dying.
She couldn't speak anymore,
she was so frail.
And then you made it
through the lines.
Slipped right through in your little
black sailboat with your onions.
And potatoes.
Some salted beef, I believe.
Every man in Storm's End
wanted to kiss you that night.
I was relieved
they did not.
Robert told me to hold
Storm's End, so I held it.
Then he told me
he was giving it to Renly,
so I gave it up.
Insult or no,
I gave it up
because Robert was my older brother
and he was the king
and I've always
done my duty.
But now I'm the rightful king by
every law of Westeros.
And when I sit the Iron Throne,
you'll be my Hand.
Your Grace...
I pray I serve you well.
I expect you'll be the first crabber's
son to wear the badge.
You're the master
of whisperers.
You're supposed
to know everything.
No man can be in all
rooms at all times.
I have many little birds
in the North, My Lord,
but I haven't heard
their songs
since Theon Greyjoy
captured Winterfell.
The Stark forces
are distracted.
Now is the time
to strike.
To strike?
My dear nephew,
you do see these men
preparing the walls
for siege?
You do understand
Stannis Baratheon sails this way?
If my Uncle Stannis lands on
the shores of King's Landing,
I'll ride out
to greet him.
A brave choice,
Your Grace.
I'm sure your men
will line up behind you.
They say Stannis
never smiles.
I'll give him
a red smile
from ear to ear.
Imagine Stannis's terror.
I am trying.
You're
an intelligent man.
I'd like to think
I'm an intelligent man.
Oh, no one disputes
that, My Lord,
not even the multitudes
who despise you.
I wish we could converse
as two honest, intelligent men.
I wish we could, too.
What do you want?
Tell me.
If we're going to play,
you'll have to start.
My brother was the youngest
Kingsguard in history.
My sister became queen
at the age of 19.
When I reached manhood,
my father put me
in charge of all the drains
and cisterns in Casterly Rock.
A most highborn plumber.
The water never
flowed better.
And all the shit
found its way to the sea.
I never expected
to have any real power.
So when my father
named me acting Hand--
You're quite good
at being Hand, you know?
Jon Arryn and Ned Stark
were good men,
honorable men,
but they disdained the game
and those who played.
- You enjoy the game.
- I do.
Last thing I expected.
And you play it well.
I'd like to keep
playing it.
If Stannis breaches
the gates, the game is over.
They say he burns
his enemies alive
to honor
the Lord of Light.
The Lord of Light
wants his enemies burned,
the Drowned God
wants them drowned.
Why are all the Gods
such vicious cunts?
Where is the God
of tits and wine?
In the Summer Isles,
they worship a fertility
goddess with 16 teats.
We should sail there
immediately.
This morning
I heard a song
all the way from Qarth
beyond the Red Waste.
Daenerys Targaryen lives.
A girl at the edge of the world
is the least of our problems.
She has three dragons.
But even if what
they say is true,
it'll be years before
they are fully grown.
And then there will be
nowhere to hide.
One game at a time,
my friend.
( Men shouting )
Jorah:
Careful, Khaleesi.
Xaro owns this city
and the warlocks have 1,000
eyes watching for you.
I found one--
a ship with
a good captain.
She leaves for
Astapor tomorrow.
- Astapor?
- We cannot stay here.
They have my dragons.
A mother does not flee
without her children.
They're not your children.
I know they call you
the Mother of Dragons
and I know you love them, but you
didn't grow them in your womb.
They didn't suckle at your breast.
They are dragons, Khaleesi.
And if we stay
in Qarth, we'll die.
You should sail to Astapor.
I'm sure you'll be safe there.
You know
I would die for you.
I will never
abandon you.
I'm sworn to protect you,
to serve.
Then serve me.
If my dragons are in
the House of the Undying,
then take me there.
That's what
the warlock wants.
He told you so himself.
If you enter that place,
you will never leave again.
- His magic is strong.
- And what of my magic?
You saw me step
into the fire.
You watched the witch burn.
What did the flames do to me?
Do you remember?
Until my last breath
I will remember.
After I have forgotten
my mother's face.
They are my children.
And they are the only
children I will ever have.
Take me to them.
We should bury them.
I'd leave 'em up
a few more days.
Sends a message.
If they haven't got
the damn message yet,
a few more days
won't help.
As you say.
But it don't hurt to let
'em rot a while longer.
What's this?
Gold for the farmer.
For his trouble.
His troubles are done.
He's feeding
the crops now.
His wife, too.
You want to keep a man
silent, you silence him.
Got as far as the farm
and then doubled back.
Walked through the stream
to throw off the hounds.
Hoped this would be the
last place they'd think to look.
You're right...
so far.
Who was that out there
hung up the gates?
Must have been
the farmer's boys.
He killed them
and burned them
and passed them off
as the little lords?
Shh, shh, shh.
They mustn't know.
Bran would blame
himself.
Osha: They'll never
hear it from me.
The little lads
have suffered enough.
( Theme music playing )
== sync, corrected by elderman ==